<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recents Article on</title><link>https://matteotomasini.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Recents Article on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matteotomasini.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo site with membership</title><link>https://matteotomasini.com/blog/hugo-site-with-membership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matteotomasini.com/blog/hugo-site-with-membership/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting interested in building sites with Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site of mine is an example, but my goal is the remaking of my wife&amp;rsquo;s site computersenzapensieri.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her site is currently created in WordPress and hosted on Aruba.it; undoubtedly presents two problems, even considering that to date it has not yet become a source of income (which we hope will soon become):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first problem is related to performance: in my opinion WordPress is a platform that requires too many resources. And if we talk about small sites with few daily visits, it is absurd to think of having to spend a hundred euros a year between hosting and SQL to avoid that a page loading takes several seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second problem is linked to the cost of hosting. For a hobby-level site like both mine and my wife&amp;rsquo;s, it is expected to take up virtually no resources and therefore can be easily hosted by mostly free services. Be sure that as a developer I am mostly against the concept that software and internet must be mostly free (we all must bring bread at home) but we must make sure to consume an adequate number of resources with respect to the type of project and therefore for small sites with few daily visits it is useless to have to deploy enormous computing powers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then stumbled upon static site engines including Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Add budget to Microsoft Azure service</title><link>https://matteotomasini.com/blog/add-budget-to-azure-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 12:49:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://matteotomasini.com/blog/add-budget-to-azure-service/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received an unexpected Microsoft Azure billing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you are sure that the resources you are using on Microsoft Azure are the usual ones every month.
It was not noticed, for example, that for a few days there were a series of events for which the logs increased dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what happened to me last month:
quiet of using the classic resources, I found myself an invoice of almost double compared to the previous months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>